# Simon Itodo

## Frontend Developer

helloitodo@gmail.com github.com/Itodo-S/ linkedin.com/in/itodo-itodo Engaged and communicative Frontend expert with 6 years of professional experience. Acquired excellent skills in unit integration testing to predict and eliminate problems, saving well over 100k in budget. Experienced in MERN Stack and JavaScript. Seeking to apply my expertise towards developing innovative solutions.

#### **Skills**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Tools & Frameworks: React, React Native, Vue/VueX, Angular, Node, Express, MongoDB (MERN STACK), SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material UI.

Other Skills: VueX, Redux,

Interests: DSA, TDD & BDD Testing, Next.js, Java, NgRx, Python. .

### **Experience**

#### **Fundhill** / Frontend Developer

MAY 2022 - PRESENT, NIGERIA

- Implemented intuitive user experience with React, React Native, jQuery & CSS on more than 4 products.
- Produced 1 robust, real-time updating back-end with MongoDB, Node.js, and Express.
- Project built through Agile Development including daily meetings with 3 collaborators and daily action item tracking via Trello.
- Managed a team of 7 junior and intern software developers, assigning tasks and ensuring growth based on company needs and workloads.

#### **Rocket Software /** Software Developer

AUGUST 2020 - MAY 2021, NIGERIA

- Developed 9+ new software solutions by analyzing system performance standards
- Analyzed systems flow, data usage, and work processes; investigated 100% of problem areas
- Analyzed 30+ user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements
- Planned, tracked, and managed deliverables on 50+ short-term sprints and 10+ long-term deployments

#### Freelance / Full Stack Developer

AUGUST 2017 - DECEMBER, 2021, REMOTE

- Developed websites using various frameworks and programming technologies including Node, Express, React, Vue, and CSS.
- Optimized web assets for speed and performance.
- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently using various resources such as Google and Stackoverflow.com.

Education

## University of Jos / Bachelor of Education

FEBRUARY 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2021, NIGERIA

FIELD OF STUDY: **EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION**